Based on the Novel by HENRI MURGER
Shit!
Did I hurt myself?
My God - blood!
- Everything okay, Marcel?
- No.
What do you think, with the middle
of my face smashed in?
Red wine.
These glasses are smaller
than a drunkard's dreams.
- Any luck with the publisher?
- No, the swine!
He said it was too long
and demanded cuts,
but with no promises
and no advance - the lout!
- Why not let me read it?
- You?
Yes, me.
You can read?
Are you kidding?
I finished third grade in Mongéo
before coming to Paris.
I'll read it at bedtime.
Why not?
You'll give me the people's appraisal
and put the publishers to shame.
The Avenger - A Play in 21 Acts
by Marcel Marx
EVICTION NOTICE
Good morning, Monsieur Marcel.
Have you forgotten
that today is the eighth?
Already? How time rushes on!
You're a bit slow
in vacating the premises.
It's already 11:30.
The new tenant may arrive
at any moment.
Allow me to find a moving van.
By all means!
But there's one little formality
to see to first:
your three months' back rent.
Would you mind?
- Of course not.
Then kindly step into my office,
so I may give you a receipt.
- When I return.
- Why not now?
I must go to the bank.
I don't carry a sum like that on me.
I see. No cash.
Then allow me to relieve you
of that little burden
so it doesn't tire you.
You think I'd carry off
my belongings in a bag?
Those are the rules.
You're not to remove so much as
a single hair until the rent is paid.
There's no hair in here,
just shirts I'm taking to the laundry
next door to the bank,
just steps from here.
Please do not misunderstand me,
but certain unfortunate experiences
have shattered my faith in tenants.
Hugo had best
accompany you to the bank.
See this man?
He's been casing this bank
for three days.
I live across the street.
His accomplice is around
the corner in an Alfa Romeo,
reading Le Monde - upside down.
I only wish to do my duty.
My life's savings are in this bank.
What do you suppose is in his bag?
Has my apartment been vacated?
Not yet, Monsieur Schaunard,
but very soon.
The previous tenant, a writer,
has gone to get a moving van.
In the meantime, you may
leave your furniture outside.
I'm afraid. If it rains,
my furniture will be damaged.
You will forgive me
if I ask your profession.
You neglected
to indicate that on the lease.
Leave the piano here and return
at once to my old lodgings
for the rest
of my priceless furnishings
and works of art.
Henri, from the Ministry of War.
It just arrived by courier.
The Ministry of War.
It must be the pension
that I've been waiting for
all these years.
At last some recognition
of my achievements.
Dear Monsieur Bernard,
courtesy demands that I inform you
of the unfortunate predicament
I find myself in
that prevents me at this time
from observing the custom
requiring that rent be paid,
especially when it's due.
Until this morning I had hoped
to honor this lo very day
by paying my rent - ah, delusion!
As I slept cradled
in false certainty, misfortune -
Ananke in Greek - dashed my hopes.
Certain sizable sums I expected
did not materialize,
but our beautiful France and I will see
better days - have no doubt of that.
The moment we do,
I shall hasten to inform you of it
and to remove from my lodgings
my precious possessions,
which I leave to your safekeeping
and to that of the law,
which restrains you
from selling them for one year.
Until then you are at liberty to use
the luxurious lodgings
in which I have resided.
In affirmation of my consent,
I hereby affix my signature.
Marcel Marx.
- Two half orders of trout.
- Yes, sir.
That's a strange order.
On the contrary.
This method yields on average
a quarter more
than ordering a full portion.
Where is my order?
I'm afraid this gentleman
got the last trout.
May I invite you to partake
of this course with me?
I would not deprive you
of what is yours, sir.
Then you'd deprive me of the pleasure
of expressing my goodwill?
In that case, sir...
Permit me to refrain
from serving you the head.
That I couldn't allow.
For if the head is
man's noblest appendage,
it's the most unpleasant
part of a trout.
Two heads! This trout is bicephalic,
a word which comes from the Greek
and means...
precisely that.
Nevertheless, I harbor no regrets
about eating this phenomenon.
The sauce was delicious.
True.
It was prepared
in the province of Béarn,
and its fine reputation
is richly deserved.
You seem very learned.
You're not from here?
No.
I come from Albania
and have lived in Paris
only three years now.
Yet you've already
mastered our language.
My nursemaid was French,
from Barcelona.
My name is Rodolfo,
and I'm a painter.
Marcel Marx, writer.
May I offer you a bottle of wine?
Only on one condition:
that I see to the coffee and the rest.
As a painter, don't you think
that Malevich's Black Square
is as lethal a blow to painting
as the school of Vienna -
Schoenberg, Berg, Webern,
and the rest - is to music?
- I agree entirely.
- Let's go.
I live just around the corner.
We may continue our discussion there.
“I floated down impassive rivers,
unguided now by bargemen's hands.
Howling natives
had hauled them up for targets
and nailed them naked
to painted stakes.”
Beautiful stuff, Rimbaud.
He and Verlaine
argued vehemently about -
Anyway, come inside.
This is where I live.
Strange. The key's in the lock,
though I put it
in my pocket this morning -
where it remains even now.
It's witchcraft! Two keys.
Someone's playing the violin.
These aren't my lodgings.
May I help you?
I was mistaken.
This isn't my apartment.
I beg your pardon
on my friend's behalf.
He's exceptionally drunk.
Wait, this is my place.
That's my finery!
And what's this?
My Turkish slippers,
given to me by beloved hands!
“Marcel Marx is hereby obligated
to vacate the premises
by noon on February eighth...”
Am I not the Marcel Marx
whom the landlord evicted?
The situation is as follows.
By law
the premises are mine,
for you were evicted,
and I paid in advance.
Yes, for the premises,
but not the furnishings.
If I pay up,
I may remove them legally -
or even illegally, if it were possible.
Thus you have furnishings
but no lodgings,
and I have lodgings but no furniture.
- Precisely.
I like the apartment.
And I've never liked it more.
- Pardon?
Never as much as now,
and I know what I'm saying.
What do you say
we lubricate this explanation?
What an amazing pipe you have.
I have an even more handsome one
for use in high society.
Would you care to try it?
- With pleasure.
You appear to be a man of musical bent.
A composer.
I'm writing a piece called
“The Influence of Blue on the Arts.”
- I can't see anyone just now.
- Why not?
Good morning.
Good morning, mademoiselle.
- There's my answer.
- I understand.
All the same, perhaps
you might lend me 1,000 francs.
I'm all out of paint,
and I can't complete my masterpiece.
You're asking a lot.
I'm broke at the moment.
Couldn't you borrow it from the girl?
I couldn't do that.
We just met yesterday.
- And Schaunard?
- No one's seen him all week.
Good-bye.
Where are you going?
To your place...
to collect what you owe me.
You won't find me at home.
I can't pay you back today.
I'm waiting for a girl.
But you can pawn my ring.
There she is.
Beat it.
What if she comes back to you?
You'd no longer have the ring.
She won't come back.
She ran off with an American.
He had a Cadillac.
It's a shame about the children.
She left them with me,
and I don't have enough to feed them.
They cry out from hunger in the night.
How old are they?
Fourteen...
nine...
seven... six...
three... two...
one...
and the youngest is just six months.
So many!
We were young and in love.
It was spring.
You look strange.
What's the matter?
I think I have fallen in love.
With whom?
I don't know...
but she's sitting over there.
She's not bad-looking.
Why don't you do something?
What if she rejects me?
I'd never get over it.
It's our custom in Albania to first -
You stay here.
I'll go speak to her on your behalf.
I will awaken in her heart a passion...
for you.
I will lie
shamelessly.
Good evening.
See that man over there?
He is in love with you.
But so am I.
Excuse me. Can I help you?
I fell asleep.
Where are you going?
Nowhere.
I arrived in town,
but my girlfriend isn't in.
I was to stay with her.
It's no use waiting.
She was taken to prison,
for three years.
What am I going to do now?
I arrived today from Rouen.
I don't know anyone here.
If you like...
I live next door.
Tell me: Are you
a proper French gentleman?
No.
I mean, yes...
but I'm not French.
I'm Albanian.
That Will do.
I'm going now
and taking the dog with me.
He sometimes makes noise
at night due to nightmares.
But why?
I can sleep on the sofa.
It's too hard for a bed.
And besides...
I'm hot-blooded,
and you are very beautiful.
- Where will you go?
- To a friend's.
He lives close by.
Sleep peacefully.
I'll be back in the morning.
Baudelaire.
“I have gone to seek lodgings.
Thank you for your kindness. Mimi.”
Where's your black coat?
Can't you see?
You've ruined it.
I'm lost.
I've been summoned by Gassot,
the newspaper czar.
He's founding a fashion magazine,
The Sash of Iris,
and plans to make me editor in chief.
If I show up in this getup,
he may change his mind.
You can't accept his offer anyway.
Gassot is a supporter of the right.
Your principles
won't allow you to eat bread
bathed in the sweat of the people.
- You're mistaken.
He's in the left flank
of the right wing in Parliament.
Just yesterday he voted
for widows' pensions.
Besides, he knows influential people
whom I'll convince to commission
compositions from you
and portraits from Rodolfo.
That changes everything.
What time's your meeting?
At 5100.
There's no time to lose.
I can polish my shoes black
so no one will notice
that one is round-toed
and the other pointed.
I need a black coat!
I'd give ten years of my life
and my right hand for one.
- Is Rodolfo the painter in?
- That's me.
My cousin recommends
your reasonably priced portraits.
I'm told they're very good likenesses.
More accurate than photographs.
He's very talented.
He won every award at school.
My son won an award,
and he's only seven.
A talented child.
This portrait you want, Monsieur...
Blancheron, from Nantes.
I'm a sugar producer.
I've even written books on the subject.
I'd like a medium-sized portrait.
Like that one. Who is that of?
My mother.
How much would one of that size cost?
Between 1,000 and 1,200 francs,
depending on whether your hands show.
- My cousin said 500.
- It depends on the season.
Paint prices vary with the season.
- Interesting. Just like sugar.
- Precisely.
- Paint me one for 1,000 francs.
- You're making a mistake.
For 200 more, he'll paint your hands
holding your book on sugar.
You simply must do it.
- Would that look good?
Exceptionally good.
Is the portrait for your home?
Yes, the living room.
Then you must be in a dressing gown.
Please sit in this chair.
Take off your coat.
I don't have a dressing gown with me.
Don't worry.
My friend will lend you his.
Marcel, please hang up
the gentleman's coat.
How unfortunate.
I'll be late for supper.
The restaurant downstairs
will send up anything we want.
I'll go order something.
I have several ideas to improve
the contents of your magazine.
For instance, one could -
this is just one possibility -
one could publish a play,
and on the facing pages
show the characters
dressed in a certain way
as if it were the fashion -
the latest fashion, of course.
One could also envision
other things, like, for example,
publishing the works of Baudelaire
in serial form -
When may I come for it?
I'll finish it tomorrow
and bring it to you.
I'd prefer to pay at once
so as not to remain in debt to you.
We're alike in that respect.
My cash is at the hotel.
You'll have it tomorrow.
Now, if you'd get me my coat...
It was very dusty,
so I had it laundered.
They only charged 40 francs.
Just add it to my bill.
I'm not paying a thing!
Shit!
The swine!
He wanted to charge me
for a few miles.
There must be 60,000 francs there.
15,240, to be precise -
an advance for producing
a sample issue of The Sash of Iris.
Here's my plan.
Secure from life's material woes,
I intend to go about this seriously.
First I'll get rid of these rags
and dress decently
so that the fashion salons
will take me seriously.
If you'll follow my example,
I can hire you
as door-to-door ad salesmen.
Until then, let a strict economy
govern our lives.
I accept wholeheartedly.
But to start with,
give me a couple of thousand francs.
Why?
As a door-to-door salesman,
I must have a car
to call on potential advertisers
in the provinces.
That's true.
Shall we order a table?
Yes. Then I can tell you
more about my new job.
There's an excellent restaurant
not far from here.
It's a bit expensive,
but we'll make it up
in the time we save.
Very well, but starting tomorrow
we shall devise even greater
means of economizing.
No more eating out.
We'll hire a woman to cook for us.
It would be wiser
to take on a manservant
who could then double as cook.
Our household would be
in impeccable order
and we'd have much more time to work
with him to shine our shoes
and see to our errands.
Then we'll need larger accommodations.
That, in any case, is unavoidable
if we mean to live in keeping
with our new position in society.
I'll be back.
A pack of Celtiques, please.
Good evening, Mimi.
You found work.
As you can see.
- And a place to live?
- It comes with the job.
Are you going to the nightclub?
I just came along with my friends.
I don't care for modern music.
I'm going to have a drink.
A glass of water, please.
- Who was that?
- A regular.
He has the manners of a peasant.
It's kind of you to see me home,
but this is nowhere near where I live.
I wish you lived in Moscow
so I might have your company
that much longer.
That's a bit too far.
We could take the boulevard.
Fancy that.
We've arrived by chance where I live.
Wouldn't you like to come up
and say hello to the dog?
Very well, but just for a moment.
I'll make some coffee.
In the meanwhile,
you may enjoy
the city view from my window.
They wilted.
Had I known, I'd have bought
plastic flowers.
What's his name?
Baudelaire.
I'm out of coffee,
but I'll make some soup.
May I kiss your hand?
You move fast.
The sooner to reach the goal.
How much is this?
A hundred francs.
Fifty.
All right. For you, 50.
How about this?
I live with two other girls.
They have a male friend in common
whom they're constantly fighting over.
I don't get it.
The man is stupid
and ugly, and married to boot.
Uglier than me?
There's no comparison.
Next to him, you're Lino Ventura.
Who's that?
An Italian movie star.
You don't know him?
Forget him.
Let's talk about me.
Why not...
move in with me?
I'm against marriage in principle,
but we could make an exception.
You'll stop working.
I'll support us both with my paintings.
And what would I do?
You'd walk Baudelaire,
clean the place -
that sort of thing.
Are you serious?
I'll clean...
and you can look
out the window at the park.
In the evenings we'll go to the opera.
My wallet's been stolen.
Do you have any money?
Just a few francs.
Police?
Your passport.
Listen, how much is their check?
Four hundred twenty.
Will you allow me to pay it?
You think you'll get your money
back from that burn?
It doesn't matter.
Then as far as we're concerned,
the matter is settled.
I have to go now.
I start work at 9:00.
I have to wait for my passport.
I'll come by your place
tomorrow evening.
I'll be waiting.
Come with me.
Why?
There's something suspicious
about your papers.
You've resided in France
for three years with no visa,
no residence permit, no work permit.
You claim you came by train from Spain,
but you choose to say nothing more.
There is nothing more to say.
Very well.
You'll spend the night here.
We'll decide your fate in the morning.
May I make a call?
My dog is home alone. - In the morning.
You're to be deported
immediately to Albania.
The flight for Athens
leaves in two hours.
If you're found
within France's borders again
without the necessary papers,
it will mean six months in jail.
May I make a call now?
Make it fast.
Mimi hasn't arrived yet.
I don't know.
Try again in a couple of hours.
Morning, Henri.
- Someone just called for you.
- Who?
He didn't say.
Could you make me a coffee?
Listen...
I'm being deported.
Will you look after Baudelaire
and my paintings?
I won't be coming back.
They'll put me in jail if I do.
Understand?
Good-bye, Rodolfo.
- A Suze.
- Problems?
No. Just thirsty.
What do you think?
1,800 francs.
Only 19,000 miles. It has brakes...
and everything.
Great.
Are you free this evening?
What's bothering you?
You don't seem too enthusiastic.
Rodolfds been deported. No papers.
Shit.
I'll go get Baudelaire.
Let's meet there tonight and haul
his paintings to your place.
All right.
Evening, ma'am.
- Are you looking for Rodolfo?
- Yes.
We were to meet here. Where is he?
He's been deported.
He was in the country illegally.
When?
This afternoon.
Is he coming back?
I don't know.
I have to go.
Shut the door when you leave.
SPRING
Hello, Musette. How's it going?
What's it look like?
How many today?
We have to go to press Friday.
Just one, but a full page.
For Printemps.
I know. They called and cancelled it.
Coffee originated in Arabia,
where it was discovered by a goat.
Balzac drank 70 cups a day.
What are you up to with that ladder?
It's the link between me
and my beloved.
Have you read Shakespeare?
Of course. He was a great philosopher.
Do you remember Romeo and Juliet?
Do I remember it?
“It was the nightingale
and not the lark
that pierced
the fearful hollow of thine ear.”
Don't you understand?
I've met a girl from a good family,
but for certain reasons
her father can't stand me
and has threatened to kill me.
The girl's name is Juliette,
and her room just happens
to have a balcony.
I came to borrow this bird
to wake me every morning
before the old man gets up.
I'd be obliged
if from now on you'd call me
Romeo Montague.
What do you think of my plan?
The Sash of Iris, hello.
It's for you, Marcel, from abroad.
All right.
Where?
What time?
Very well.
Forget about your Juliette.
We have to go.
- Where?
- The border.
I'll explain on the way.
Let me have a few hundred.
- There is no money.
Where did it all go?
I paid the printer
so they'd give me the magazines.
You could have left them there.
We need a picture for the cover.
Hold still.
Now let's go.
There he is.
Shall we go?
We can make Paris by morning.
- When is Mimi in?
- Mimi isn't here anymore.
But they stop in almost every evening.
Who's “they”?
Mimi and Francis, her boyfriend.
Why do you ask?
I'm an old friend.
Thank you.
Good evening.
How are you?
- Fine.
Someone was asking for you.
- Who?
An old friend. He's sitting over there.
I believe The Crossing of the Red Sea
is finished.
I feel empty.
If you manage to sell it,
we can pay the rent.
Perhaps you could
come down on the price.
I won't sell it for less
than 200 francs.
I've already put
over 10,000 francs'
worth of paint into it.
What if the landlord calls the police?
You still don't have
a residence permit.
Come in.
What a surprise.
Would you offer our guest
a glass of water?
To what do I owe this honor?
I was so inspired by your portrait
that I've decided
to become a collector.
I'm now looking
for a relatively large painting,
and I thought of you.
You're in luck.
I just finished this one
and intended to send it off
in the morning with some other works
to an exhibition in New York.
But if you'd care to make an offer...
as an old customer...
I like the work very much.
I'll give you 1,000 francs.
- You're joking.
- 1,200.
2,000.
1,400.
1,700.
1,500...
and two tickets
to the opera this evening.
Opera is a dying art form,
but all right.
Go pay the rent and then get dressed.
You and Musette can go to the opera.
I'll wait outside.
I have to talk to Marcel.
Poor girls.
They were never meant
to live like this.
Being men, and thus stronger
in every respect,
we bear up joyfully
under every misfortune.
We don't sink into depression
if our outfit isn't always
neat and tidy.
But for women it's different.
The simplest frock brings them joy,
and one can't fault them for that.
On the other hand,
the market for art and literature
has been bustling recently.
We'll soon be earning
nearly as much as porters
at the Gare de L'Est.
It's true.
Works of art are selling like pancakes.
Then it's agreed.
Tomorrow we take the girls shopping
to indulge their feminine whims.
Sunday we'll go on a picnic
in the countryside.
What about me?
You have two days
to find yourself a companion.
It's not our fault if your appearance
sparks no interest in the opposite sex.
But if you have no luck,
you can still come along...
as our driver.
Monsieur, there's a call
for you in the kitchen.
Madame...
your eyes are like two moons.
Let's hope it doesn't come
to more than 600 francs.
And never come back!
They didn't like it?
Idiots!
They tried to discourage me.
They said I should break
my brushes in two
and jump out the window.
Let's go borrow some money from Marcel
and go out to eat.
I gave you
a cash advance.
I want it back
in two days.
Not three or five.
Two days.
Good luck...
and good-bye.
What was that all about?
He's mad that I serialized my play.
Says it didn't suit the magazine's
style and that readers complained.
What readers?
Besides, as editor in chief,
I set the style.
He was just the publisher. Capitalist!
- I'm hungry.
- Me too.
Come eat at my place.
I happen to have a little money.
While we're at it,
I can play my latest
composition for you.
I'm going to leave Marcel.
When?
Tonight.
I've already packed.
Does he know?
I didn't dare tell him.
I'm going back to Strasbourg.
There's this farmer there.
He's not great-looking,
but he's sweet...
and dependable.
Why?
Marcel doesn't need me.
All he loves is his books.
Yesterday I pawned
my ring for rent money.
I left the money on the table.
When I came back, he'd taken it...
and spent it all
on first-edition Balzacs.
Poor Marcel.
He'll forget me in a week.
In any case,
quicker than I'll forget him.
That's how men are.
Will you see me to the station?
- Of course.
I'll miss you.
You must come visit!
I'll send you the fare.
The man's rich.
I promise.
Write to me care of general delivery.
Why general delivery?
I don't know.
How's it going, Mimi?
Fine.
Can I give you a ride?
You can drive me home.
Yes, darling.
I found work.
You needn't have.
I can't go on living like this,
never having any money.
I can't breathe.
It's like I'm suffocating.
I'll open the window.
That won't help.
Besides, it's already cold in here.
Shall I light a fire in the stove?
There's no wood or coal.
Some old poems of mine.
I thought I'd publish a collection...
someday.
At least they'll provide some heat.
I'm going for a little walk.
Don't be too long.
Hello, Rodolfo.
Hello, Mimi.
I love you, you know,
but life is hard.
Yes. I understand.
I drink.
Glass after glass
To forget all about my wife's friends
I drink.
Glass after glass
To forget all my troubles
I drink.
Any old swill
As long as it's strong
I drink.
The cheapest stuff
It's rough
But it passes the time
Is life really such a lark?
Is it really so exciting?
I ask
Those two questions
AUTUMN
Is it worth living?
Or loving, only to be cheated on?
I ask those two questions
But no one ever answers
And so I drink
Glass after glass
What?
Nothing.
It's very good.
The voice of the people
is the voice of God.
EVEN MOSES USED BLANCHERON SUGAR
That there is known as
turkey with truffles.
Look at the color of that leg of lamb!
Lamb is the favorite food of the gods
and also of my godmother,
Madame Chandlier.
And what about those trout?
They're superb swimmers.
They climb rapids as quickly
as we'd accept an invitation
to dinner this evening.
That fruit is known as pineapple.
I almost got to taste one once.
Speaking of fruit,
I wouldn't say no
to that pheasant there.
Why this profusion of delicacies?
You don't know? It's All Saints' Day,
a great family celebration.
Would you care to spend
the evening with me?
No money.
How much have you got?
I don't understand.
I've lost my appetite.
Same here.
I can see
that a phantom from the past
sits at this table.
But if you intend
to waste away to nothing,
you could do so
just as well on a full stomach.
Am I disturbing you?
Come in.
I'm so cold.
I happened to be passing by
and saw the light in the window.
I lost my apartment a week ago,
and I've been wandering
the streets ever since.
I'm posing for artists these days,
but it doesn't pay much.
Oh, I only show my face and hands.
They've promised to pay me tomorrow.
Then I'll move back into my apartment.
- Where are you two going?
- To get some cigars.
In Havana.
We'll be back tomorrow
sure as arrows loosed by a steady hand.
Where have you been?
Don't ask any questions.
Just let me sit here by your side.
It's so warm here.
I'll stay until tomorrow. All right?
It's going to be very cold here.
Good.
It'll be just like before.
I'll clear the table.
The warmth has made me dizzy.
I can hardly stand up.
You have a fever.
I'll help you into bed.
Schaunard and I will go get a doctor.
You stay here
and keep Mimi company.
I was awake the whole time.
Rodolfo still loves me.
What about you?
I never stopped loving him.
Then all is well.
I'm going away forever.
What are you talking about?
I'm going to die soon.
Look.
You believe me now?
If I'd stayed here
with Rodolfo,
everything would be fine now.
Poor Rodolfo.
He has to take care of me once again.
But not for long.
The last dress he buys me
will be white.
Don't talk like that.
You'll get better.
Rodolfo has gone for a doctor.
It took me an hour
to climb the stairs yesterday.
But if I'd found
another woman here with him,
I'd have thrown myself
right out the window.
Rodolfo knows everything.
She must go to the hospital -
my hospital.
I'll call an ambulance.
I have a car.
You must be brave.
I can ease her pain,
but I can't save her.
She'll live until spring at the latest.
I can keep her in a private room,
but I must warn you:
Though it may seem cruel,
it's very expensive.
I'll find the money.
Who painted this? Becker?
Open the curtains.
Spring is here,
and I want to look outside.
It's so grey in here.
Why don't you pick me some flowers?
She's dead.
Shall we come with you?
That's all right.
I need to be alone.