Having heard Of Jesus' presence...
she appeared with a jar of fragrant oil.
She knelt at Jesus' feet...
And weeping she poured her tears over his feet
which she then dried with her hair,covered with kisses...
And anointed with the fragrant oil.
Seeing this...
said the Pharisee who had invited Jesus
to himself:
If this man is a prophet...
he would know who this woman is:
A sinner.
But Jesus answered:
When I entered your house, you did
not pour water poured over my feet.
But she has washed my feet
Washed with her tears.
And with her hair dried.
And therefore her countless sins were
forgiven her.
For she showed much love.
This woman was Mary Magdalene.
The Body of Christ.
Amen.
Hello, mom.
- Hi, honey. Everything okay?
Yes yes.
And what time will you be there?
Then we can have a nice lunch together.
Shall I pick you up from the station?
Okay. But are you coming with Laurent's car?
That's none of your business, Mom.
Excuse me.
Fine.
Well, until tomorrow then.
Love to both.
I'm waiting for you here.
It's going to be really good.
- Yes, I hope so.
Go ahead.
Give him a kiss from me.
Correctional institution.
Marie-Claude Perrin.
Thank you very much.
- Have a nice day, ma'am.
Michelle?
Thank you for bringing it.
When do you want to go there again?
In ten days or so?
Good.
Come in, the door is open.
Everything okay?
Cup of coffee?
If there is time.
- Yes.
They don't come for one.
And with all the traffic jams...
Does your daughter
now have her driver's
license? - Yes.
You are still the only one without.
I slept badly last night.
- Logically, it's a full moon.
Maybe that's it.
Thank you.
- That's good for the mushrooms.
Where are the mushrooms?
Come on, there were
many last year.
Look here.
Check this out.
- Yes, a boletus.
Yes, a boletus.
And a beautiful one, too.
Marie-Claude, look at this.
Is this a good one or not?
- No, that's a fake cockscomb.
Wonderful.
I walk on a little bit,
I have to go cook.
I love to hear the stories.
Absolutely. Get your fill.
Hello.
Grandma.
- Bye, my darling. Sweetheart.
Everything okay?
- Yes.
Bye, honey.
- I'm not kissing. I have a snotty cold.
Good trip?
- No, getting out of Paris was a disaster.
Lucas, your bag.
- I cooked delicious food for you.
We already ate a sandwich.
- I'm hungry.
Very good, dear.
We'll make it a nice vacation.
Who is she talking to?
- Dad.
What next?
Arguing about the vacation because of me.
- Well, no.
Listen carefully.
It's not you, it's them.
Come. We are going to cook together.
I have delicious fresh mushrooms.
I don't like those. - Of
course you do. You're
just going to taste them.
With some butter and garlic...
it's delicious.
- I don't like garlic.
Valerie, would you put your phone
put your phone away for a moment?
Stop it, mom.
I have enough stress as it is.
Is it tasty, dear?
Can I have the mushrooms?
It smells delicious. Is there garlic in it?
- Yes.
You didn't?
- No, you've spoiled my appetite.
Sorry, I just quit smoking.
I am rather irritable.
Have you gained some weight?
In my opinion, no.
Watch out, at your age
you shouldn't let yourself go.
By the way, how is Marie-Claude doing?
Up and down, but pretty good.
Is that deranged son of hers
still in jail?
Stop it, Valérie.
Everyone deserves a second chance.
The jerk didn't.
That boy has never had it easy.
I do sometimes?
How can you stand up for him
after what he did?
What did he do?
- Nothing. Eat your plate.
Anyone have any quiche or mushrooms?
- No thanks.
I spoke to a notary friend of mine.
If you donate to me now,
it will save you taxes after you die.
Is grandma going to die?
- Well no, I'm in perfect health.
Put the house in my name.
You don't like this house, do you?
It's not about that,
it's about value.
For the future, for Lucas.
But I have already given you my flat in Paris
already gifted you.
So what?
Does anyone want cheese?
- No, thanks.
Then I'll get dessert.
- No, I've already eaten too much.
I do, grandma.
I'll get it.
Thank you, dear.
It's nice weather for a walk.
- Good idea, yes.
Move over.
- But I need to make two phone calls.
And I still have to work.
Is the Internet better yet?
Yes, the entire village now has fiber optics.
Hallelujah.
What are we going to do this week, Grandma?
- Whatever you want, dear.
Walking, reading, watching movies...
cake baking.
I promised mom: no tablet.
- Very good.
But with me you may occasionally be
disobedient.
That's our little secret.
Do you want to play games with me?
- If you teach me.
Grandma?
- Yes, dear.
Don't you ever get bored here?
- No.
I like to be close to nature,
the river, the trees.
I enjoy the birds singing.
I don't miss Paris at all.
But you are all alone.
- Well, no.
I have my friend Marie-Claude.
This is a must-see view.
Isn't this beautiful?
Where is her home?
There. See that?
Beyond those trees. Do you see it?
- Yes.
A small house.
- Yes, but still...
What about you?
Would you want to live here?
Yes, maybe.
But Mom would never want it.
Yes, your mother always
hated it.
We're going back.
- Okay.
What's going on?
I'm sorry, what happened?
- A woman became unwell inside.
You are?
- Her mother. This is her son.
Go soon.
Bernard, what is it? -
Your daughter called us.
She's unconscious now.
What does she have? -
We're going
to find out in the ER.
It looks like poisoning.
The mushrooms.
- Did she eat them?
At noon.
Freshly picked with Marie-Claude.
Did you eat them, too?
- No, I wasn't hungry.
And the boy?
- I don't like mushrooms.
Can we come with you?
- Just come to the hospital.
Marie-Claude?
Do you know more yet?
- No, we are still waiting.
The doctor.
And?
Everything was fine. We got there in time.
Her stomach was pumped out.
It will be fine.
- I am glad.
Terrible, I had prepared the food.
- Something like that can happen.
But you must make a statement
at the police station.
The police? - Better
right now than for them
to come to your home.
We have to report the poisoning.
Of course, yes.
The doctor said you have to rest.
- No, I'm going back to Paris.
Are you sure you can drive?
Sleep here tonight.
Don't leave until tomorrow.
Stop it, mom.
We're going home.
We?
Lucas should stay.
What about his sleepover?
- I don't trust you anymore.
It was an accident.
- I was almost dead.
We could have been dead, too.
- No, you didn't eat it.
And you know Lucas doesn't like it.
You poisoned me.
You are toxic.
- What?
Accident or not, you are dangerous.
I'm not leaving my son here.
I want to stay with grandma.
- We're going home.
What about my vacation?
- We'll see about that with your father.
Some sandwiches for the road.
We don't have any use for that.
- What do you mean?
Rather transfer 500 euros,
I'll make it by the end of the month.
Here, dear.
- Thank you, grandma.
And have a check-up.
That's wise at your age.
Police station.
Tell.
Valérie did not press charges.
- The idea.
Would you like some coffee?
- No, thanks.
Did they say anything about the past?
No, nothing.
I feel guilty.
I should have checked your mushrooms.
Valérie thinks
I really wanted to kill her.
She always blames you for everything.
Doesn't want me to see Lucas anymore,
I'm so sorry.
What are you doing here?
Where is your mommy?
- There.
Do you want to go to her?
- Yes.
Michelle?
I'm not waking you up, am I?
- No, I'll be right there.
I am so happy.
If he finds work and reintegrates quickly,
he may receive punitive damages.
Very nice.
- Yes.
But jobs here are not
for the taking.
The important thing is that he gets out
and stays straight.
This is Valérie's voicemail...
Boy...
Happy to see me?
- Overjoyed.
It's not hard, you know.
Bye, gentlemen.
Goodbye.
I am lucky with this beautiful weather.
Are you okay?
- Yeah. And you?
Michelle is waiting for us.
- Shit, Michelle.
Always a real lady.
- Bye, boy.
Good to see you.
- Sweet that you came along.
Right? Come with me.
Need help?
- It's not hard.
Get out of here fast.
Before they change their minds.
- Imagine.
Where do you want to eat?
Doesn't matter.
The food there was incredibly gross.
How about La Beursaudière?
- Delicious, but not cheap.
My treat.
- That's sweet.
As long as they are not mushrooms.
Shit, how delicious.
To freedom, dear one.
Thank you, momma. Michelle...
To our health.
And no more silly things.
Finito.
Does anyone want dessert?
- Sure.
Can we have the dessert menu?
- What plans do you have?
I can work in a warehouse in Auxerre.
But Auxerre...
You can rent there.
- Yes, I can.
But what would you like to do?
I'd rather stay around here
And start a cafe.
That would...
It takes money to do that.
- I know.
Have you made a choice?
- Not yet.
Shit, profiteroles.
Ma? Michelle?
Yes, good idea.
Michelle?
- Just coffee.
One coffee, two profiteroles.
- Coming up.
You could work for me.
How so?
The garden is big. And I've been neglecting
the vegetable garden lately.
Wood needs to be chopped,
cleaned up.
Yes, why not? I am all for it.
Fifteen euros an hour, black?
- Great.
Thank you, Michelle.
See...
I'd like you to chop enough wood
for the whole winter.
Here...
lie all the tools you need.
And here is the vegetable garden.
There's a lot to do there.
I didn't have the oomph.
So you go first...
Remove all the weeds
between the plants.
And after that...
you pick the pumpkins
and put them in the shed there.
After that, you throw them over.
All done.
- Great.
Shall I pay you right away?
- Please, I'll see my buddies tonight.
How many hours is it?
I started by two o'clock,
so about three and a half hours.
Okay, then I'll make it four hours.
Look, please.
Top. Same thing tomorrow?
Morning.
- Okay.
Very good.
Bye, ma'am.
Has the code changed?
- Yes.
Can you let me in?
- Where should you be?
At my daughter's house, on the sixth floor.
I used to live there myself.
Can't you call her?
- I want to surprise her.
Thank you.
Hello.
What are you doing here?
Since you didn't answer, I just came here
here. May I come in?
What did you say to her?
- That I only have a few years left.
That I wanted to make up with her
And I wanted to see my grandson.
Is he at home?
- No, he is at school.
And will he be allowed to come
come to stay?
No.
She was talking about a year
to his father in Dubai.
What does Laurent think?
- He keeps out of it.
Their separation is painful enough.
Consult a lawyer. A grandmother
has the right to see her grandchildren.
But with those mushrooms
I forfeited that.
Unbelievable. I gave her
my flat in Paris...
I send her money, I have consulted a notary about the house.
No thank you, nothing.
It's about my money to her,
and nothing else.
After all that slaving away for our children
we get stinkers.
You're not allowed to say that.
- Sorry, but that pisses me off.
Yes?
Were you here? Hello, Vincent.
I'm going out with my buddies.
- What buddies?
Will I see you tomorrow, Michelle?
- Yes, see you tomorrow.
I hate to say it.
But with our children...
we did nothing.
Cheers.
- To your health, darling.
Here.
- Michelle.
Do you want to throw this away?
I don't need it anymore.
What is it? No, I can't.
Why not?
- Because.
You'll probably see your grandson again.
- No.
Too painful. I'd rather throw it away.
- But Michelle...
Need to hear.
Do whatever you want with it.
But I want it out of here. OK?
An antidepressant can help.
But it is more important that you stay busy.
Find an activity you enjoy.
I don't feel like doing anything.
The congregation is looking for volunteers.
You can lend a hand.
Or at church, at catechism class.
Catechism lesson?
Is that a joke?
Sorry.
Anyway...
Ever since I stopped seeing my grandson,
I have trouble with children.
I am afraid that I am going senile.
Why do you think that?
Are you forgetful?
I don't know.
It has been since...
that mushroom story
with my daughter.
That could have happened to anyone.
You know that.
Yes, but it had never
happened to me before.
Next time pay better attention.
No, I will never pick mushrooms again.
You should not feel guilty
or punish yourself, Mrs. Giraud.
It was not intentional.
Right?
I don't remember.
Marie-Claude?
- Michelle?
Did anything happen?
- No.
Vincent is not here yet.
- He left early. I didn't hear him.
He forgot his phone again.
We would clean up the garage.
Today?
- Yes.
Maybe he went to Auxerre first?
Possibly.
Sorry, I must have forgotten.
Doesn't matter.
- Thank you. Love.
Love back.
Hello. You're looking for?
Don't you recognize me?
- No.
Marie-Claude's son.
Weren't you...
- No, I'm free again.
A long time ago.
- Yeah, crazy, right?
May I come in?
Yeah, awful, no? I should get rid of
my mother's furniture soon.
Sugar?
- No.
Okay...
What have you come to do in Paris?
Looking you up.
Me?
- Yes.
To... talk about Michelle.
What is this?
Did she send you?
No, not that, but... Just...
Your mother is sad.
You are hurting her.
Am I hurting her?
Are you making fun of me?
You keep her grandson away from her.
You can't do that.
Without her, you wouldn't have been here.
- What are you talking about?
Why are you meddling with this?
Why are you lecturing me?
Doesn't matter.
Your mother is a good person.
You shouldn't treat her that way.
I can't follow you. What exactly is
your relationship with my mother?
Tell us.
We know about her shitty past.
And from your mother.
They worked together.
Didn't you have a problem with their stuff?
I do.
Don't you see how they damaged us?
You just got out of the slammer.
And I'm so unhappy
I could jump out the window.
She disgusts me.
To throw up.
- You shouldn't talk
about your mother
that way. - No?
How should I
talk about my dear little mistress?
Like about a saint?
I need a fag.
Hello. Yes?
Bye, Laurent.
What?
No way...
How did that happen?
And Lucas?
Yes.
Yes, yes...
Well, yes...
Tomorrow.
Call... Are you calling me?
Good.
I'm waiting.
You're home.
Had a moment's warning.
Michelle was worried.
Where have you been?
Vincent, what is it?
Nothing.
What did you do?
Where were you?
- Paris.
Paris? What did you have to do there?
I went to see Michelle's daughter.
- Valérie? Why?
To talk to her, to tell her mother's
life is so hard.
What are you meddling with?
Michelle was sad.
I wanted to help.
I tried to talk to her.
And then...
Then what?
she fell.
Fell?
- Off the balcony, the stupid bitch.
You can't be serious.
It was an accident.
We stood on the balcony
and we were getting words and...
Did you push her?
- No, it was an accident.
My best friend's daughter.
No ma, don't cry, dammit.
Does Michelle know?
- I think so, she calls all
the time. Don't cry.
It is not true.
Are you going to tell her?
Are you recording?
Listen, Ma. I don't want
to go back to jail. I really don't.
Ma...
Hello, Michelle?
Inspector...
- Let her in.
Sorry, sir.
Valérie was in divorce.
She was having problems at work.
Money worries.
And.
Yes?
I was not the mother
that she had wanted.
This is more common.
Yes, but...
I used to be a prostitute.
My daughter has never
been able to accept that.
I see.
Could it have been suicide?
I don't know.
It could.
She was very unstable.
Has she sent you any messages recently?
- No.
Were there people
who were angry with her?
Not that I know of.
Good.
Perhaps autopsy is necessary.
Before we decide to do so...
I want to take you to her apartment
to see if you see anything remarkable.
How much longer?
- Three months.
Boy or girl?
I don't need to know that.
What about the father?
- There is no father.
Sorry.
- Never mind.
Bye, ma'am.
And?
No traces of breaking
Or of a struggle.
A full cup of coffee.
- With only the victim's fingerprints.
Is it there?
Up here she had cigarettes lying around.
You need the steps for that.
I think she went to get cigarettes
and slipped.
Where was her body?
- Right below.
Are you okay?
To me, it's clear.
She fell from this.
I ask permission for burial.
- No autopsy?
Not needed.
- OK.
I just...
one last question.
Do you still have contact
with the prostitution world?
No, that's over. I'm retired.
Since when?
- Since...
Before the birth of my grandson.
Checked her background?
- She had posh clients.
Has had problems on several occasions
with pimps.
She worked for quite a long time.
Hello.
Laurent...
Come.
Did you come here this morning?
Yes.
You know, Michelle...
Valérie and I loved each other.
But in a wrong way.
I feel guilty.
You can't help it.
We should have stayed together.
- It wouldn't have made any difference.
We were still arguing that morning.
About what?
About Lucas, as always.
Sorry, you will have to go outside.
The apartment must now remain sealed.
See.
A huge desert. Pools...
skyscrapers. And look here...
There's my office.
Beautiful, isn't it?
Yes.
You will like it there.
Always nice, warm weather.
There is even a French school
You can make friends there.
No.
No what?
I don't want to go there.
You can't stay here by yourself, dear.
Let's go. Up.
Otherwise, you'll be late for school.
Come on, kid. You can do it.
Darling.
Breakfast is ready.
What are you thinking about?
Nothing.
Do they still call you Parisian at school?
Sometimes.
Don't get caught off guard.
OK.
I'll pick you up.
- I'll take the bus. Just like the others.
Well then.
See you later. Take good care.
Bye, ma'am.
Lucas is doing well, you know.
In the beginning it was difficult.
But now it's going well, I think.
Mom, you killed me.
How can you say such a thing?
Nobody killed you.
According to police, it was an accident.
An accident?
Yes.
Or suicide, if you will.
You would rather.
You were so unhappy. Because of
your divorce and all your problems.
You now have what you wanted.
No.
Yep.
My son.
How is Lucas doing?
- He's starting to find his feet.
Doesn't he find it tough?
You got me.
You are holding your own.
When I think of Valérie,
I hear her reproaches, her angry temper.
Somehow I am relieved that she is no
longer there. And I don't even feel guilty.
Can I have a cigarette?
What about your son?
- I'm afraid he'll do stupid things again.
Well, he's serious now.
He's working on his project.
And how did he
get that money for his café?
Something you are not telling me?
Didn't he say anything?
- No. Then what?
I gave him that money.
He pays it back later.
I wanted to get him going.
Why did you do that?
I like your son.
He helped me too.
What is it?
Hopefully, he
doesn't end up in jail again because of you.
Marie-Claude.
How is she doing? -
They are keeping her
overnight for observation.
Did she break something?
- Not that, but...
They are doing some research.
It doesn't look good.
Why hadn't you said anything about the money?
- Why should I?
As a result, she was upset.
- She was?
Lucas is waiting for me.
- How is he?
Good. How come?
- Well, his mother is dead.
Will you keep me informed?
Lucas.
Open up.
Why are you sitting there doing nothing?
Nothing.
Come and eat.
You are not very talkative tonight.
You know...
I did see the bruise on your forehead though.
What happened? Did you fight?
Did they beat you?
- I'm not hungry anymore.
I'll go to my room.
What are you watching?
Photos from the past.
They say you're a whore at school
Who says so?
The big boys.
Well...
I used to be.
In Paris, I did that for a few years.
You didn't have to do that.
- Sometimes you have to.
Because someone is forcing you.
I find you disgusting.
I get that.
But... it was a way
to keep our heads above water.
So that your mother was
to lack nothing.
I know it's no ordinary work...
it was my job.
Is that why Mommy was mad at you?
Yes.
She was ashamed of me.
Something like that
is difficult for children.
But that is now a thing of the past.
It's all about us now.
Especially about you.
And I will help you.
I will make sure that you are well,
that you're happy.
You look like mom.
Michelle, how cool that you came.
Speaks for itself.
Ma's in.
- Was she allowed out of the hospital?
I'm going to see her soon.
- How are you? Sit down.
Hello.
Marie-Claude.
No but, you look cute.
I made myself up.
Good thing, right?
He fixed it up nicely.
It's only going to cause misery.
Why so morbid?
Have faith in your son.
It's going to work.
I have to go back tomorrow.
More research?
Are you worried?
- No, fatalistic.
Is everything going well here?
Dancing?
Let's celebrate love
while we still can
and not wait
until death knocks at the door
let's celebrate love
while we still can
when I feel like dancing
I dance now
it is true
we cannot change the world
I know
but believing that for a moment
does you good
let's celebrate love
while we still can.
Your grandmother can dance well.
- How long have you known grandma?
- For a very long time. From Paris.
Did you do the same thing she did?
Does the cap come off?
- Don't.
Sorry to hear.
Look at that old whore.
That blonde slut.
What did you say?
Vincent, don't.
Let's have some fun.
He never changes either.
- Bring on the music.
Good morning, Vincent.
- Ha, Michelle.
Everything okay?
A glass of white.
Did you close late?
- Sure.
But it won't be a party every night.
Glad Marie-Claude could be there.
- Certainly.
But she's not doing well.
Pros.
She shouldn't be so gloomy.
Something is bothering her.
But she doesn't tell me anything.
Vincent... I would like to...
What?
That you do something for me one more time.
- What are you doing here?
I came to pick you up. Michelle says you're being bullied. Is that true?
Those guys over there?
- No.
By whom, then?
By those big guys over there.
- Those over there? Okay.
Wait for me at the bus stop.
I'll be right there.
What did you say?
- That I have been in prison.
Really?
Not that I'm proud of that, mind you.
But they were impressed.
What did you show them?
Don't touch.
Do you recognize it?
Not so. Sucker.
Why was Vincent in prison?
Sorry?
- Why was he in prison?
He used to do stupid things.
Did he kill someone?
Well no. Why do you say that?
Because prisoners are killers.
- Not always. Fortunately not.
Comes with your plate.
Why doesn't he have a wife?
I have no idea. Since he lives
with his mother, it might be difficult.
Ask him.
Are you doing well in school?
- Yes.
Do you have good grades?
- Yes, it's easier than in Paris.
But keep doing your best, though.
Don't worry, Laurent.
Lucas works hard and is very serious.
Okay. So you like the countryside?
- Yes.
Will you come live with me next year?
- We'll see.
I would love that.
Don't worry.
He'll come all right.
Thank you, Michelle.
Vincent?
Are you okay?
Grandma's cake.
Don't laugh.
I made your favorite cake.
That's sweet.
But I have less and less of an appetite.
Do your best.
You should not despair.
It's too late, Michelle.
- No, there is always hope.
The cancer has spread.
Did they say that?
- I wanted them to tell the truth.
But surely there is a treatment.
Too burdensome and pointless.
I need to tell you something
before I go.
Was I a bad mother?
Did Vincent go
fallen off the tracks?
No.
We did our best.
And your son is doing well now.
He is serious about his café.
Promise to keep watching him.
I promise.
You know...
On the day of Valérie's death...
Vincent was not in Auxerre.
He was in Paris at the time.
Vincent's good intentions
always backfire.
The important thing is
that he means well.
'That I quenched my thirst...'
Yes.
'That I quenched my thirst,
A good twenty paces downstream from thee.
So that I would not muddy your waters.
'You do, ' Grimbeard exclaimed.
And last year you spoke ill of me.'
'Then I wasn't born yet, the lamb said.'
- 'Then it was your brother.'
'I don't have a brother.'
Yes, Vincent?
No way...
When?
My goodness...
Did she suffer?
Yes, yes...
Okay.
Much love.
I'll stop by later.
Are you sad?
She was my best friend.
My sister.
Who are they?
- Girlfriends.
Where is Vincent?
- He was outside smoking.
Go get it soon.
Vincent?
They are waiting for you.
- I can't.
You know, when my mother passed away.
I went to her funeral.
You're bleeding.
- I bumped myself.
Please.
Hold on.
Shit, say.
The life of Marie-Claude...
has known light and shadow sides.
But we don't judge her.
For God does not judge...
While He knows everything about us.
To Him, we are like an open book.
He has only one purpose:
to redeem us.
Let us remember in our prayers
To all our memories.
To our beloved Marie-Claude.
See, I'm coming to see you.
I found your favorite plant.
Which was also on your balcony.
I heard that you were here.
Can I have a word with you?
- Yes.
Shall we go to the café?
- No, that's not a good idea.
I would rather go to your house.
Fine.
So the baby is here?
- Yes.
A girl.
- Great.
What's her name?
- Eve.
The first years with my daughter
were wonderful.
We were very close.
Only later did the bond deteriorate.
Did she have a father?
Of course.
But he did not care about her.
He only gave us money, too late.
Money is not love
and is never enough.
Sit down.
I have doubts
about Valérie's cause of death.
How so?
I'm not sure if it was
was an accident or suicide.
I fear it was possibly murder.
Because of the mushrooms?
- No.
I don't suspect you directly either.
Who is it?
- Your friend Marie-Claude's son.
Vincent?
Why him?
- We received anonymous letters.
And you know his past.
He has been in prison.
Do you remember where he was
on the day of Valérie's death?
I know that, yes.
Vincent was here.
He was working in the garden
when my son-in-law Laurent called me...
with the news of Valérie.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Would you like coffee?
No, thank you.
By the way.
Does his phone indicate
that he was in Paris?
No, we polled it here.
He could have left it here on purpose.
- Well, no.
Young people never go out without a phone
on the road.
He is not that young.
Surely you gave him money for his cafe,
after the death of your daughter?
Yes.
A loan to get him started.
- Has he paid it back yet?
Not yet.
But I trust him.
Nice gift.
Vincent has not had it easy.
He's a little...
Like a son to me.
His mother and I were very close.
She asked me to help him.
Grandma?
Are you all right, dear?
- Yeah.
Did it go well in school?
This is my grandson, Lucas.
He lives here.
His father lives abroad.
This is Vincent, Marie-Claude's son.
Hello. I recognized you already.
And you are?
- She is from the Paris police.
In reference to Valérie.
Do you mind
if I ask Lucas a few questions?
No.
Are you coming?
Out for a while?
- Good.
To the swing?
Beautiful garden.
Do you like it here?
- Yes, very much so.
Do you get along with grandma?
- Yes.
And do you see Vincent often?
Yes, he picks me up from school
and we play soccer together.
- Is he nice to you?
- Yes.
In the hall of the building where you lived,
there was a security camera.
When I took another look
one more time...
I found images of people
who came in before her accident.
You see residents going in.
And in one picture we see you.
See? That's you.
This is where you hold
the door open for a man.
You can't see his face
Because of his hoodie.
Do you remember?
Did you know this man?
Could it be Vincent?
No, he wasn't.
Are you sure?
Yes.
Vincent, are we going to play soccer?
- Let's go.
May we?
- Yes.
Did it go well?
Did he cooperate well?
- Yes.
Since the death of his mother, he has been...
- I know.
I baked a cake for him.
Would you like a piece?
Gladly.
Everything okay?
- And you? It's been a long time.
Come here.
Shall I take your bag?
- No need.
The car is right there.
Had a good trip?
- Yes.
How are things?
In Paris, the study and so on...
Good.
Through a friend of Dad's
I found an attic room.
Nice.
What exactly are you studying?
Art History.
- What can you do with that at all?
I don't know that yet.
- Of course you don't.
Not yet.
Do you have a girlfriend?
No.
- No?
And you still not married?
- Not that I know of.
Grandma.
- Dear Lucas.
How nice to see you.
Come here.
Quickly go inside. It's cold.
Will you eat with us?
- Gladly.
Close the gate behind you.
Shit, what a delicious quiche.
Can I have some more?
Sorry, canned mushrooms.
- Delicious.
Do you like mushrooms these days?
- Always have.
Is your café running well?
- Sure.
Especially by all the Parisians
who have settled here.
Want to go to the cemetery?
It doesn't have to be, you know.
I was just there yesterday.
Your mother's grave is nice and clean.
I brought flowers.
I don't know.
I don't like coming there either. So...
I'd rather take a walk in the woods.
Just like before?
- Yes.
I baked a cake. A slice?
- Sure enough.
I'm going to get it.
- No, let me.
Thank you, dear.
He is standing on the table.
Grab plates as well.
That little one has grown up.
- Sure.
It's a beautiful boy.
- Yes.
He looks like his mother.
Would you hand me my bag?
It's on the chair.
The keys to the house.
It's yours now.
Thank you.
After I die, you may sell it.
That's what your mother wanted.
No.
I want to keep it.
Let me help you.
Easy, guys.
I can still stand on my own two feet.
That way.
So...
And the pinball machine?
- I sold that one.
Really. I needed money.
Too bad.
- You put a lot of hours behind it.
Mom...
Where is grandma?
She was just walking behind us.
Michelle.
Grandma?
- Michelle?
I walk to the car.You look here.
Michelle.
- Grandma.
Vincent...