WHITE MEADOWS
A Mohammad Rasoulof movie
Hassan Pourshirazi
Younes Ghazali, Mohammad Rabbani
Mohammad Shirvani, Omid Zare
Bahman Maleki, Ava Darvish
Yasaman Mohebahari, Stamak Nazari
Production Manager:
Golamreza Ahmadi.
First Camera Assistant:
Bahman MAleki
Photo:
Kourosh Minimum
Assistant Director:
Daryoush Ebadi.
Set Designer:
Shahram Karimi
Make-up:
Mehrdad Mirkiani
Voice Recording:
Mohammad Mokhtari
Sound Engineer:
Amir-Hossein Ghasemi
Music:
Mohammad Reza Darvishi
Editor:
Jafar Panahi.
Cinematographer:
Ebrahim Ghafouri
Screenwriter, Director:
Mohammad Rasoulof
CAPTION: @keserb
- It's coming.
- Hi
-Aleykum hello
-I hope you're not too tired.
-I hope you too.
-You are late.
-There is no time.
- How long ago did it happen?
- About 8 days.
-Woman or man?
- Woman.
-Are you a relative?
-He has no relatives.
Just an old mother, but mourning
There are many people who keep it. She was so beautiful!
Waiting until you come and get it
We buried his body in salt.
Poor girl died too young
and no one knows why.
All the women were jealous of him.
-Have you ever seen him?
- No.
His mother is waiting for you in pain.
This is it, please come in.
-Hi
-Aleykum hello.
It's good he died.
As he walked, his body would shake.
The heart of anyone who saw him would be shaken.
One day I was sitting right here...
When he looked at me as he passed...
My whole body felt a sweet shiver.
but he didn't stop.
He looked directly into my eyes.
I followed him.
Good thing he died. men its
He felt humiliated by.
It takes you to the water and more
It makes you very thirsty.
God save us.
If we had a grave
and if we buried him here,
Young people buried his grave at midnight
They would dig it up and take it out.
The men must go!
We want to remove his body.
A few men should remain to carry the body.
-We will stay. You can go.
Hello.
Who are you?
Nassim
You puppy! What are you doing here?
I can explain!
Do you want to take me back?
If you do, everyone will look at the dead woman
He will know that you want to look.
What will you do? No!
No! No!
Get off my boat!
Help... help!
My eyes are burning!
I can't swim!
help for god's sake
help me!
I don't know how to swim!
Tell everyone you want to see the naked woman
I will tell you. For God's sake, help me!
Then...
What were you doing on my boat?
I'm talking to you.
I will tell you.
Yesterday two men took them off the island if I obeyed them.
They said they would help me leave.
They took the body out and took it as their own.
They said they would bury him.
Nobody should notice.
I could find my father.
He's been away for a long time.
They said you go everywhere with your boat.
I can find him if you take me along.
Please take me with you.
I swear I will be your slave.
Nobody will know.
Alright.
I will take you with me...
on one condition
You will keep your mouth shut!
My job is heartache
It's about people who are.
If they find out you can hear,
They no longer open their hearts to me.
You must be deaf and dumb.
I will be both deaf and dumb.
As long as you take me with you
Say you will take it.
Get together.
Can I ask you something'?
Really people's tears
Can you turn it into a pearl?
With tears he cleanses the dead from their sins
They say it can purify.
Where are we going?
Straight ahead, son!
Mind you, not a word.
Remember, Deaf and dumb.
- Definitely
-Didn't I say you wouldn't say a word?
- Hi. Mr. Rahmat.
- Hi. What are you doing?
These poor things are too much
He died because of salt water.
The salt increases too much.
They go blind when they put their heads under water
It happens and they die of hunger.
Morad Bey's mother had a dream.
I'm researching it.
You are a good man. Let's go.
Hi!
- Hello!
-We were waiting for you.
-Salam aleykum
-Rahmat has arrived, mother!
He's not sane anymore.
I have come to end your tears.
I came to listen to your heartache.
Would you allow me?
The fairy has been in the well for 300 years.
Sea water has never been this salty.
Fairy to enter the well
When he came out of the sea in anger...
The sea wasn't even half as salty.
People did not commit many sins back then.
Tell them not to sin so much.
If they sin less,
It will turn into fresh, clean water.
And there will be no smoke from the fire.
The world will turn green.
Mr. Morad!
Mr. Morad, I found it! I found it!
Open the door for me.
After all, your dream is so wrong
It wasn't, Mom! - I found it!
bird cadavers
I was collecting and found this.
Next!
Much obliged
-Did you give your name?
- Yes.
Next !
Hello aleykum.
The child is deaf and blind.
Speak your mind.
- Thank you very much.
- Next.
- Hi.
- I found Khojasteh. He wants to see you.
- Tell him to come.
Get in!
- Hi.
Wishes are being collected.
You will deliver them.
As you wish.
I will be ready.
Next !
The jars are safe in the fairy's hands
must reach it somehow.
Go down as far as possible.
The further you go,
Wishes come so quickly.
Go quickly and carefully,
so the jars don't break.
They are entrusted to us, do you understand?
Climb quickly when I pull the rope.
If the sun rises and you're still there,
will be cancelled. Do you understand?
I can't walk properly.
What if I can't climb again?
And if I fail,
Khojasteh wishes to the fairy
Won't they say he couldn't deliver?
I just got married.
If I die, what will happen to the poor girl?
I'm too heavy. I can't even walk.
There are so many words in jars.
What are you saying?
You see everyone is waiting, go now.
However you like
Go!
Go! Go! Go!
Faster!
Go faster!
He must climb up!
- Come back!
- Come back! Come back!
Khojasteh!
Khojosteh, come up!
No thanks.
Take it.
After each ceremony, the container of tears
Clean carefully with clean water.
Otherwise, it will remain in the tear salts.
The container must be cleaned. So that the one who cries...
Every single tear of yours
He knows he is rewarded.
Otherwise, they are taken and
They can never cry again.
I think this job is difficult.
For 30 years people
I collected your tears.
But I enter that ceremony every time.
and suffering with someone and
I sit in tears...
And it feels like the first time
Tears should be treated with respect.
They are valuable. Single
One drop should not be wasted.
how difficult this job is
It will take a long time for you to realize it.
-What is your father's name?
- Cenobar.
Senobor?
What did he do?
- He was a shepherd.
It's weird that I don't know him
I know most of the people here.
What brought him to the sea?
I was so young, I don't remember.
They say: He led his flock to the pastures,
He spent too much time in the sun and his brain dried out.
Then one day that sea
of water and soil...
He wanted to go to places where it wasn't salty.
Where do you want to look for it?
Do you have an address?
No, I just know he's getting old.
Hi!
You always came alone.
I never imagined you with anyone else.
He's not a stranger. He is my son.
He is deaf and dumb.
May God heal him.
Any new news?
-Did it finally rain?
-Not yet.
This is such a small sky.
It brings dark clouds
but it's not raining.
If the sky carries grudges.
There's nothing you can do
If the sea does not mediate
The sky does not rain.
Hi.
How are you?
Light the fire!
Prepare yourselves, witnesses!
Prepare the bed!
Don't be afraid!
You are going to a beautiful place.
This is destiny!
I don't want to be a bride!
Tell them I won't be a bride!
Don't let them take me, for God's sake!
What did you do with your tears, you whelp?
-I will pray for your health.
-I will pray for your happiness.
Help! I don't want to die!
I don't want to go to the sea.
I am scared.
God help me!
I don't want it!
This bride is pure and no one
I certify that you did not touch him.
He just loved the sea and now
She goes into his arms!
I confirm that this bride is a virgin!
He loved the sea and sent it to him!
The most beautiful young girl on the island
I confirm that it is.
and the people sacrificed him to the seas!
Blessed be! of happiness
can enjoy it.
The sea is a beautiful groom.
Blessed be your son-in-law.
to intercede with the sky...
Tell him to make it rain.
Thus you will be Blessed.
Don't worry, your daughter will be happy.
My sweet girl!
For a visit, I will have to go to the sea.
- What happened?
- I saw him.
He went after her.
He was far away when I saw him.
Are you sure you are Rahmat's son?
Yes, he was a deaf, dull child.
I sent two people after him.
Until I think of something
Don't say a word until.
Don't hit me, don't beat me!
For God's sake, don't shoot!
Don't hit him!
Don't hit!
Stop, your tongue is loosened. It's a miracle!
God forgave him, so should you!
I'm on fire
I'm on fire.
I'm on fire. My wounds are burning.
Salt water will keep your wounds clean.
Sleep.
I'm on fire.
I'm thirsty
This.
You can't drink water, you die.
I'm thirsty.
This.
I'm on fire
My wounds are burning.
This.
Get up.
What did you do with your tears?
Don't you want to tell?
My eyes are burning.
What did you do with your tears?
My eyes are burning!
Stand up son, we are here.
My son.
I will be back soon.
We are here today as always...
For the man with a thousand faces...
You all know the man with a thousand faces.
With a new face every day
is coming; cheer you up
and to make you forget your sorrows.
With what face today?
No one knows what will happen next.
Every day is new, more joyful
We see a face.
If you can hear me, a man with a thousand faces,
With what face do you see people today?
will you cheer? Like this.
How will you make us happy? Eh?
He wants to say something.
Okay, he says: if someone is miserable...
Feel the pain of that young man
should put it in his bag and throw it away.
The bag is ready, now it's deep
Put your heartaches inside.
Spread your pain
Throw away your pain
Throw them away.
At work.
Here.
From the bottom of your heart.
Now he's cheerful with a thousand faces
You can see the man.
Hello everyone.
Congratulations.
We have a wedding today.
The bride should sit here.
Now a white wedding dress
You wear it, you will marry the groom...
handsome, rich and good-natured monkey?
Yes?.. The first time no one
I know you didn't say "yes".
Second time: "yes"?
No? Then why did you wear a wedding dress?
Look, once again...
You either say "yes" or it
You don't deserve to wear the dress.
But what about the groom?
Don't stay away from happiness.
Listen to your elders.
Will you say "yes"?
Won't you say "yes"? Under any circumstances?
He won't say "yes". wedding canceled
It was done, there is no beauty by force.
But come on, we worked hard for this.
We invited many guests,
We prepared meals...
We spent a lot of money. Everyone to you
He came to pay his respects.
Think a little more, don't ruin your life,
The groom is a sweet-natured monkey.
and rich!
You should see the paintings he made.
He painted the sea red.
The old man said to him: "The sea
"Dye it blue, not red."
"No, the sea is always blue
"Who said it was?" he said.
The old man was very angry.
He didn't forbid him to paint, he just
He asked him to paint it correctly.
Are you ok'?
How are your eyes? Can you see?
- Yes.
-What do you see? Don't talk nonsense.
His eyes are bad. He sees distortedly,
That's why he speaks garbled.
He is not even aware of himself.
My eyes are your mercy
He can see that it is.
I'm thirsty, water.
Rahmat, my nose itches.
Is it good?
His vision is distorted, but he doesn't know what it is.
- Is it ready to be washed?
- Let's get it.
Again.
Wash your head well.
Wash his head too.
pour some on
Wash your ears.
Hold it.
What should I do?
Go up, up!
Go up!
Look at the sun!
Climb and look at the sun!
-My eyes are burning!
-I said look at the sun!
- I'm going blind.
-Look at the sun, your eyesight will come back!
Climb up or I'll come and take you out!
Look at the sun!
Climb up!
My eyes are popping out!
Look at the sun!
Look at the sun and your eyesight will come back!
Open your eyes.
What color is the sea?
I can still see it.
I can still see!
- Very good.
I know But what color?
She is so beautiful.
-Today is a different color.
-It's blue, isn't it?
Blue?
Even kids know it's blue!
Come on, say it's blue and we'll get rid of it.
Say it's blue. to heal
They want to pour animal urine into your eyes.
You can see the color you want,
But say it's blue!
Today is a different color.
Brother, blue for your mother's head
Say it is, otherwise they will beat you up.
There is no way. Only
The solution is monkey urine.
I'm holding it. dock.
Open your eyes, open them
On fire!
Cry...
It relaxes you.
-The old man ordered him to leave.
- Let him stay, I'll take care of him.
If it stays; everyone is bad
will have eyes
Dad, stop repeating this. It's contagious.
If he stays, everyone will have evil eyes.
-What do we say to his mother?
-Leave it to me.
If you let it stay,
won't paint.
This has nothing to do with the picture.
His eyes and brain are bad
and his heart is full of pain, do you understand?
and her heart is full of pain
It's full, do you understand?
And his disease is contagious.
Would you like to eat something?
Don't worry.
Your eyes will see clearly.
Have you visited many places with this boat?
What?
What's at the end of this sea?
I don't know.
You are finally here!
-You look ready to leave again.
- I'm so tired of this place.
If it were you I would watch the sea all day
wouldn't you have to watch it?
How long has anyone been
Do you know that I didn't see it?
I know you're lonely.
Help me, I brought you a guest.
Get up, we arrived
- Guest?
You mean a prisoner?
Yes, even two
- Take it
-I do not accept prisoners.
He won't be convicted!
Accept it or not, you know.
As long as you're in charge here...
I must hand them over to you and go.
Been separated for a long time, for a while
I'm thinking of living my own life.
If they don't let me go,
They should bring a bride, I said.
And you will bring me a bride
You promised many times.
What happened to your words?
I have to go.
Do you want to go?
-I have work to do.
-Spend the night, get some rest.
I said I had work to do.
I'll feel less lonely if you stay.
You're always wasting my time.
Spend the night here, you
I have a lot to say.
- What is the difference between them?
- What difference does it make?
I need to know.
When they're better
They talk about themselves.
This is too young.
sit here
What have you done?
I am fed up.
Go on a cruise...
and sea water is not salty...
and the land is a salt marsh
I want to go to a place where it's not there.
I miss my sheep. .
Wake up, get up!
This is alive.
This person died.
What color is the sea? Blue!
Don't wait, it's not like that!
Come back, stand up now!
Go back, go up now!
Run run!
Hurry up! Go up!
What color is the sea? Blue!
What color is the sea? Go up, quickly!
Come closer! from the stairs
down, not like this!
Come back! Here go down.
What color is the sea? Blue!
Let's run!
Stop!
Run, don't stop!
To the right, to your own right!
Come back, run!
Walking!
What color is the sea? Blue!
Hello aleykum.
He asks if everyone is okay.
Heaven should be praised.
CAPTION: @keserb